A Guide to the Los Angeles Poverty Department (LAPD) Collection, 1986-2000
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Los Angeles Poverty Department (LAPD) Collection, 1986-2000
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2001-014
8.6 cu. ft. 7 boxes; 1 oversize folder
The collection includes papers, photographs, and audio materials from the Los Angeles Poverty Department (LAPD), a LA-based theatre and arts group. Materials date from the founding of the organization in 1985 until about 2000.
Los Angeles Poverty Department (LAPD). (Theatre Company)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Los Angeles Poverty Department (LAPD) Collection was donated to Special Collections in 2001.
Historical Note
The Los Angeles Poverty Department is a theatre and community activism group made up of artists, residence, and people who work on Skid Row in Los Angeles, dedicated to creating change and sharing stories. The group began in 1985 and remains active within the community and performs throughout the world. More information about the group and its mission is available on the Los Angels Poverty Department website: http://www.lapovertydept.org/.
Scope and Content
The collection includes papers, photographs, and audio materials from the Los Angeles Poverty Department (LAPD), a LA-based theatre and arts group from the time of the organization's founding in 1985 until about 2000. The collection is organized into two series: Papers and Photographs and Audio (Cassettes and Reels).
The Papers and Photographs contains administrative documents, grant applications and proposals, programs, promotional materials, announcements and publicity, production notes and pictures from a several performances and productions. The Audio series includes cassette tapes and reels with performances, interviews, and panel discussions, as well as unidentified recordings.
Arrangement
The collection in arranged in two series: Paper and Photographs and Audio (Cassettes and Reels). For the most part, the Papers and Photographs are the original order received at the time of their donation. Audio materials are organized by material type; cassette tapes were removed to an appropriate box (Box 7).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Community theater
Contents List
- Papers and Photographs
  - Articles About Participant's Activities (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Arts Inc., Art Matters, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Arts Inc., Art Matters. folder 2-2 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Brody Grants, CCF, folder 1-3, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Brody Grants, CCF, folder 2-3 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Brody Grants, CCF, folder 3-3 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - California Arts Council Grants, CAC org. Support, folder 1-2, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - California Arts Council, CAC Org. Support, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Cultural Affairs, Who's War, Red Beard, CAD, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - CAC- Artist in Residence, folder 1-3, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - CAC- Artist in Residence, folder 2-3, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - CAC- Artist in Residence, folder 3-3, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1-12)
  - CAC Organization- Support (Box-folder 1-13)
  - CAC, folder 1-21995-1997 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - CAC, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - CAC Multicultural, folder 1-2, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 1-16)
  - CAC Multicultural, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Cafe, St. Vincent's (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Cold, Wet Weather Festivals, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Cold, Wet Weather Festival, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - JM Workshop Originals (Box-folder 1-21)
  - CDCF Funding for CIE, 1994 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Change/Exchange Materials, folder 1-4 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Change/Exchange Materials, folder 2-4, 1994 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Change/Exchange Materials, folder 3-4, 1994 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Change/Exchange Materials, folder 4-4, 1994 (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Change/Exchange 1995 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Change/Exchange 1996, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 1-28)
  - Change/Exchange 1996, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 1-29)
  - City of LA Cultural Affairs, 1990-93, folder 1-3 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - City of LA Cultural Affairs, 1990-93, folder 2-3 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - City of LA Cultural Affairs, 1990-93, folder 3-3 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - City of LA Cultural Affairs, 1993-95, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - City of LA Cultural Affairs, 1993-95, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Contraband Project (Includes NEA consult), folder 1-2 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Contraband Project, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Contracts (Box-folder 2-8)
  - CLRA (Box-folder 2-89)
  - Cultural Affairs Grant, AA Organization, LAPD Single Room Occupancy Housing Corp (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Cultural Affairs Grand (Box-folder 2-11)
  - Flinthdge Foundation (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Fundraising Proposals (Box-folder 2-13)
  - Goat Island (Box-folder 2-14)
  - Grant Denials, folder 1-5 (Box-folder 2-15)
  - Grant Denials, folder 2-5 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Grant Denials, folder 3-5 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Grant Denials, folder 4-5 (Box-folder 2-18)
  - Grant Denials, folder 5-5 (Box-folder 2-19)
  - Grant Research Project, Residency Research, folder 1-4 (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Grant Research Project, Residency Research, folder 2-4 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Grant Research Project, Residency Research, folder 3-4 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Grant Research Project, Residency Research, folder 4-4 (Box-folder 4-4)
  - [Homeless] (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Inner City (Box-folder 3-6)
  - James Irvine Foundation, 1991 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - J.M., 09/28/1994 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - LAPD Inspects Houston, TX, Diverse Works, The Road Show (Box-folder 3-9)
  - LAPD Inspects Houston, TX, The Road Show (Box-folder 3-10)
  - Irvine, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 3-11)
  - Irvine, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 3-12)
  - LAC Multicultural Entry Grant, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 3-13)
  - LAC Multicultural Grant, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 3-14)
  - LAPD Journal (Box-folder 3-15)
  - LAPD Group Journal #1 (Box-folder 3-16)
  - LAPD Group Journal #2 (Box-folder 3-17)
  - LA Project (Box-folder 3-18)
  - Los Angeles: Downtown Strategic Plan (Box-folder 3-19)
  - LAPD- JOHN (Box-folder 3-20)
  - LAPD- BJ KRIVANEK, Fiscal Recruiter (Box-folder 3-21)
  - Lannan (Box-folder 3-22)
  - Liberty Hill Foundation (Box-folder 3-23)
  - Liberty Hill Foundation, 1988 (Box-folder 3-24)
  - Men Falling Through Walls, Street Shows, JM Presentation (Box-folder 3-25)
  - Mailing USA (Box-folder 3-26)
  - Maine Festival (Box-folder 3-27)
  - National/State/County, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 3-28)
  - National/State/County, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 3-29)
  - National Endorsement for the Arts, NEA:Inter-Arts (Box-folder 3-30)
  - NEA:Inter-Arts (Presenting and Commissioning) (Box-folder 3-31)
  - NEA, folder 1-2, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 4-1)
  - NEA, folder 2-2, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 4-2)
  - N/S/C, 1992-95, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 4-3)
  - N/S/C, 1992-95, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 4-4)
  - NEA: Expansion Arts, folder 1-4 (Box-folder 4-5)
  - NEA: Expansion Arts, folder 2-4 (Box-folder 4-6)
  - NEA: Expansion Arts, folder 3-4 (Box-folder 4-7)
  - NEA Expansion Arts, folder 4-4 (Box-folder 4-8)
  - NEA Theater 1998-99, Lollapalooza 1998-99, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 4-9)
  - NEA Theater 1998-99, Lollapalooza 1998-99, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 4-10\)
  - National Performance Network, 1991-92, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 4-11)
  - National Performance Network, 1991-92 (Box-folder 4-12)
  - NYC, Dancing in the Streets, Homelessness Concert (Box-folder 4-13)
  - North Carolina (Box-folder 4-14)
  - Public Welfare Foundation, 1993-94, Ruth Mott, 1993-4,, Workshop Support (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Press Budget, Insurance, Misc. (Box-folder 4-16)
  - RACE- Pascal Rambot (Box-folder 4-17)
  - Residencies Documentation, Seattle, Portland, Minneapolis (Box-folder 4-18)
  - Residencies Documentation, Irvine, CA, Amsterdam (Box-folder 4-19)
  - Residencies Documentation, London, US International (Box-folder 4-20)
  - Santa Monica Arts (Box-folder 4-21)
  - Statement of Artistic Direction (Box-folder 4-22)
  - Summer Workshop, 1993, folder 1-4 (Box-folder 4-23)
  - Summer Workshop 1993, folder 2-4 (Box-folder 4-24)
  - Summer Workshop 1993. folder 3-4 (Box-folder 4-25)
  - Summer Workshop 1993, folder 4-4 (Box-folder 4-26)
  - Taking Back, 1998, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 4-27)
  - Taking Back 1998, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 4-28)
  - "You Don't Need a Home to Vote" (Box-folder 4-29)
  - Activity Reports, Recruitments, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Activity Reports, Recruitments, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Colorado Dance Festival (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Donor Newsletters Board (Box-folder 5-4)
  - Europe (Box-folder 5-5)
  - Grant Proposals, 1986 (Box-folder 5-6)
  - LAPD Handwritten Documents, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 5-7)
  - LAPD Handwritten Documents, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 5-8)
  - LAPD Inspects Chicago and Philadelphia (Box-folder 5-9)
  - LA Men's Place (Box-folder 5-10)
  - LAPD Programs, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 5-11)
  - LAPD Programs, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 5-12)
  - LAPD Schedule (Box-folder 5-13)
  - LAPD- Articles/Media (Box-folder 5-14)
  - Mailed Envelopes (Box-folder 5-14)
  - Minneapolis, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 5-16)
  - Minneapolis, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 5-17)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box-folder 5-18)
  - Newspapers- Full Issues, folder 1-2 (Box-folder 5-19)
  - Newspapers- Full Issues, folder 2-2 (Box-folder 5-20)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Misc. Notes (Box-folder 5-21)
  - "No Stone for Studs Schwartz" (Box-folder 5-22)
  - Performance Notes (Box-folder 5-23)
  - Poverty Debt Workshop (Box-folder 5-25)
  - Production Folders (Box-folder 5-24)
  - Pamphlets, Flyers and Guides (Box-folder 5-26)
  - Robert Show (Box-folder 5-27)
  - Workshop Flyers (Box-folder 5-28)
  - "Buffalo Who" Photos 1994 (Box-folder 6-1)
  - "Call Home" Photos 1991 (Box-folder 6-2)
  - "I Was Sleeping With My Eyes Open" Workshop (Box-folder 6-3)
  - John Malpede- "Olympic Update" Photos, 1984 (Box-folder 6-4)
  - "Jupiter 35" Photos, 1989 (Box-folder 6-5)
  - "Give Up All Your Possessions and Follow Me" Photos, 1993 (Box-folder 6-6)
  - "LAPD Inspects Chicago" Photos, 1990 (Box-folder 6-7)
  - "LAPD Inspects Houston" Photos, 1992 (Box-folder 6-8)
  - "LAPD Inspects Philadelphia" Photos, 1989 (Box-folder 6-9)
  - "LAPD Inspects San Francisco" Photos, 1988 (Box-folder 6-10)
  - "LAPD Inspects the Twin Cities" Photos, 1991 (Box-folder 6-11)
  - LAPD Programs- folder 1-4 (Box-folder 6-12)
  - LAPD Programs- folder 2-4 (Box-folder 6-13)
  - LAPD Programs- folder 3-4 (Box-folder 6-14)
  - LAPD Programs- folder 4-4 (Box-folder 6-15)
  - Misc. Organization Information (Box-folder 6-16)
  - "No Stone For Studs Schwartz" Photos, 1987 (Box-folder 6-17)
  - "Red Beard, Red Beard" Photos, 2000 (Box-folder 6-18)
  - "The Road Show" Photos, 1993 (Box-folder 6-19)
  - "South of the Clouds" Photos. 1986 (Box-folder 6-20)
  - "Virtual Reality" Photos, 1996 (Box-folder 6-21)
  - Oversize Materials (Folder 1)
- Audio (Cassettes and Reels)
  - Change/Exchange Performance, 07/30/1993 (Box-item 6-1)
  - Give Up All Your Posessions and Follow Me Performance, June 26, 1993 (Box-item 6-2)
  - Interview with John- Agents and Assets, 2001 (Box-item 6-3)
  - Jupiter 35 by LAPD- excerpt. Marco scene (Box-item 6-4)
  - LAPD- "Buffalo Who?" (Box-item 6-5)
  - LAPD does Irvine, 01/06/1991 (Box-item 6-6)
  - LAPD Inspects Chicago/Washington D.C. (Box-item 6-7)
  - LAPD Inspects the Twin Cities (Box-item 6-8)
  - LAPD Inspects Washington D.C. (Box-item 6-9)
  - LAPD- "Red Bead, Red Beard" March, 2000 (Box-item 6-10)
  - LAPD- Temporary Quarters: Hit and Run (Box-item 6-11)
  - "Race" by Pascal Lambert, June, 1999 (Box-item 6-12)
  - Virtual Reality, 1995 (Box-item 6-13)
  - Change/Exchange- LAPD Panel (Box-item 7-1)
  - Change/Exchange- Community Arts Panel, 07/21/1994 (Box-item 7-2)
  - Community Arts Panel 1994, tape 1-3 (Box-item 7-3)
  - Community Arts Panel 1994, tape 2-3 (Box-item 7-4)
  - Community Arts Panel, tape 3-3 (Box-item 7-5)
  - C/E Discussions with LAPD Members (Box-item 7-6)
  - Discussions with Providers (Box-item 7-7)
  - C/E Evaluation, tape 1-2 (Box-item 7-8)
  - C/E Evaluation, tape 2-2 (Box-item 7-9)
  - Goat Land (Box-item 7-10)
  - Jim Gillian Jazz Groups (Box-item 7-11)
  - J.M Talks in San Jose (Box-item 7-12)
  - LAPD Member Panel, 1995, tape 1-4 (Box-item 7-13)
  - LAPD Member Panel 1995, tape 2-4 (Box-item 7-14)
  - LAPD Member Panel 1995, tape 3-4 (Box-item 7-15)
  - LAPD Member Panel 1995, tape 4-4 (Box-item 7-16)
  - Social Services Panel 1995, tape 1-2 (Box-item 7-17)
  - Social Services Panel 1994, tape 2-2 (Box-item 7-18)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 1-9 (Box-item 6-1)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 2-9 (Box-item 6-2)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 3-9 (Box-item 6-3)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 4-9 (Box-item 6-4)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 5-9 (Box-item 6-5)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 6-9 (Box-item 6-6)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 7-9 (Box-item 6-7)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 8-9 (Box-item 6-8)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 9-9 (Box-item 6-9)
  - Fill Music Sound Recordings (Box-item 6-10)
  - Sound Recordings- 11/30/85 Workshop (Box-item 6-11)
  - "The Morning Magazine", "Al Creitz vs. Hip Special Worker Skit", "Al Creitz vs. Hip Special Worker Skit", "Scene One from Play", 11/27/85 (Box-item 6-12)
  - LAPD Board Content Sound Recording (Box-item 6-13)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 2-9 (Box-item 6-2)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 4-9 (Box-item 6-4)
  - Miscellaneous Sound Recordings- Reel 7-9 (Box-item 6-7)